There are levels to AI coding. Beginners
are prompting, they're waiting for their
agents to finish, they're reviewing the
work, and then they're prompting again.
But, experts figured out how to automate
the entire workflow. And in this video,
I am going to show you what the absolute
experts are doing. So, this is all of
what we're going to be going over in
this video, but first, which tools do
you use to start? So, I use all of the
agentic coding tools out there. I have
to, it's part of my job, and so I've
tested and have experience with all of
them. Right now, my two primary coding
agents are Cursor and Codex. Cursor is
definitely one of my favorite for
multiple reasons. Number one, you can
have models from different AI companies.
OpenAI, Anthropic, even Cursor
themselves has their own model. And not
only that, Cursor was one of the first
to have cloud agents, and I'm going to
get into more details about what cloud
agents are, but just know it's a really
great feature. So, this is Codex,
definitely one of the best coding
harnesses out there. What I like most of
all about it is the first of all, the
design. It's beautiful. And second, it
is able to describe what it's building
in a really concise way, and just the
overall interaction with the model, the
vibe of the model is great. I really
appreciate how concise the explanations
are. So, you can see that right here. It
runs commands, then it gives you a
one-to-two sentence summary of what it
just did, and so on and so forth. And
that's what I really appreciate. I
cannot stand having to read essays about
what the agent is doing. I want it short
and sweet. Now, Claude Code is great. I
don't use it all that often just because
I ran out of quota so quickly and so
frequently, I just stopped using it as
much. Devin is fantastic and Factory are
all fantastic options. Highly recommend
all of them. They all have different
harnesses, they all have different pros
and cons. You just need to go out and
use them and figure out what works best
for you. Next, we're going to be talking
about rules, agents.md,
and also Claude.md.
So, what are these? These are the ways
to tell these tools exactly how you want
them to work, exactly what your workflow
is, how you like your commit structured,
how you like your commit messages
written, the personality of the model
when it's replying back to you, your
coding preferences in general. This is
where you define them. Now, basically
all of these tools support agents.md
with the exception of Claude Code. They
have their own Claude.md. Cursor has
rules, but it's basically just writing
to the agents.md file and it very much
does support agents.md. All right, so if
you're going to be using it in Cursor,
go ahead and go into preferences, then
on the left side, you're going to click
this little button, rules, skills, sub
agents, and then right here are where
the rules are written. So, if I click
into one, here we go. Keep responses
short and simple, avoid showing code
snippets. I can just click in and see
it. Respond in plain English only, avoid
talking about specific parts of the
code. Then, we have our project
approach. Avoid writing one-time scripts
in permanent files, don't mock data
except for tests, etc. And then, of
course, we have the agents file right
here. These are actually learned
preferences that Cursor writes to as you
use it. And you can just add an
agents.md file to any project that
you're working on. You can define
exactly how you want the model to
behave, exactly what your workflow is,
your deployed process, everything.
That's where you put it. And so, if
you're not using agents.md, I highly
recommend you do. Just start with the
vibe of the model, the personality of
the model, define how you want it to
behave and talk to you. And then, from
there, you can learn what you like to
do. All right, next, one of the most
important things that you need to use,
skills. I cannot stress this enough. You
want to use a lot of skills. Anything
that you do more than once, make it into
a skill. Go browse off-the-shelf public
skills. There are so many great ones you
need to use. They are so very important.
And so here are some examples of what
you're going to use skills for. First,
anything that you do more than once. If
you do it more than once, it should have
been a skill to begin with. You create
the skill and rather than having to,
let's say, copy-paste a prompt over and
over again, you simply type  and
then invoke the skill and then it will
do that thing for you, whatever it is.
So here's an example. I type , it
brings up a list of commands and skills
and what we're going to do is we're
going to type auto review,
hit enter, and then hit enter again. And
now that skill is invoked and it's going
to do the auto review skill. And next,
one of the most important tools that I
use for reviewing all of the code that
AI is writing for me is Greptile.
Greptile is fantastic. They're also the
sponsor of this video. Let me show you
how I actually use them in my coding
workflow. So I have a Greptile account,
I connect it to every new repository
that I create, and it automatically does
this incredible thing. As soon as a PR
is opened, Greptile goes in and starts
reviewing the code. Check this out,
right here. So here's a PR that I
opened, fix skill import context and
scan false positive. Greptile summary.
It gives me a summary of what changed.
It also gives me a confidence score,
zero through five. And that is the
confidence that if I merge this code, if
I merge this PR, it's going to land
successfully and there's not going to be
bugs or errors. And it details the
different files that changed and what
changes were made to them. It gives me a
nice flowchart of what was changed in
the pieces of code. and then it tells me
specifically issues that it would fix
and gives me a prompt to copy-paste into
AI to fix it. Griptile is used already
by the biggest companies in the world,
including Nvidia, Compass, WorkOS,
Zapier, Brex, Scale. So many different
companies use Griptile. I highly
recommend it. I'm going to drop a link
down below so you can go check them out.
Let them know I sent you. It really does
help our channel to let them know that I
sent you. So please go check them out.
They've been a great partner. Links down
below. Next is when you have
domain-specific
rules. So if your company has a specific
writing style, if you have a certain way
you like to write up GitHub issues, if
you have certain company information you
want to provide to the agent, do that
all within a skill. Next, and maybe one
of the most important uses of skills,
tool instructions. Tools are executable
pieces of code that can be called from a
skill. So if you have a specific way
that you kick off tests, for example, or
if you want to only wrote a subset of
the tests, or how to use a certain API
or CLI, all of this can be defined in a
skill, and that's how you use it. You
don't have to redefine all of it. You
don't have to provide that context about
what the API endpoints are, what
responses it should expect. It's all
going to be defined in that skill that
you can just reuse as many times as you
want. And the cool thing is the agents
can actually discover and determine
which skills it should be using at
runtime. So you don't actually have to
say  you know, whatever the skill
is, the agent will know when to use it.
And then last, quality gates. So if you
want to say, "Okay, before we open a PR,
I want to run all tests locally, and I
want to make sure we have 100% pass
rate, and if we don't pass, fix the
test." If you want all of that process
defined and easily invoked, you can put
that in a skill. And by the way, there
are tons of off-the-shelf skills that
you can use right now. So, for example,
here's one called Agent Skills. It has
61,000 stars on GitHub, and it gives you
everything you need for your development
cycle. Everything from refining an idea
to specking the PRD, implementing the
code, testing, QA, and deployment. It's
just all there. It has very opinionated
ways of doing things. So, if you like
that, great, just use it. All you have
to do is grab the URL, go to Cursor, go
to Codex, go to Factory, wherever you
want, put it in and say, "Install this
skill." And then you just hit enter, and
it's going to install the skill for you.
You really don't need to do anything
else, and then it'll be available.
Sometimes you have to restart the
software for the skill to become
available, but that's about it. The next
two things I want to talk about are
different but very related. Automations
and loops. Automations allow you to
prompt your model automatically
depending on some trigger. I'm going to
show you what that means. And loops
allows your agent to run indefinitely
until it hits a certain goal. And I'm
going to show you that specifically as
well. This is what the best of the best
Agentech coders out there are using. So,
in most tools, I'm going to show you
this in Cursor and in Codex, there is a
first-class feature called automation.
So, this is Cursor. In the top left, I
have this automations right here. We're
going to click it, and what we can do is
click this create new automation button
right there. The first thing you need is
a trigger, then you're going to give
your agent instructions, a prompt, and
then you can also include memories or
add tools or MCP servers. We'll keep it
simple. So, as I just showed you with
Greptile, I want my agent, after
Greptile leaves its comments, to
automatically review the comments, fix
them, and then resubmit the PR. And so,
let's just automate that. Let Let show
you how. The trigger, we'll select
GitHub, and we can see pull request
opened. So, that's when a pull request
gets opened. Now, there's one problem.
The pull request will get opened and
trigger the automation, but Greptile may
not have had enough time to actually
review the code. So, what do we do?
We'll just say, "Wait until you see
Greptile's comments on the PR." Now,
because I wrote that, it will literally
just wait, which is nice. Then, once you
do go through each of them, each of the
comments, and address the comments. Once
you're done, push the new code back to
the PR. And that's it. Now, every single
PR that opens, Greptile will review it.
This agent will wait until the comments
are there from Greptile, then it will
address the comments and push the code.
Make sure you're selecting the right
repo, so I'm going to select Astro Hub
by anyone. And then last, before we
create this, Cursor does this cool thing
where it automatically identified tools
that we might need to make this
automation work. So, it highlighted this
address the comments. Some tools might
not be configured yet. Let's click
tools, go down to the GitHub tool,
comment on pull request, and then we're
done. Hit create, and that's it. Now, we
have that running automatically. Super
useful, and also in Codex, it's kind of
the same thing. Click up here to
automations. You can either create via
chat and just describe in natural
language the automation you want, or you
can click this drop-down, create it
manually,
and then you use a title, you add the
prompt, you can select which repo down
here, how it's scheduled, you can give
it memories and tools. It's very similar
to how they do it in Cursor. I cannot
recommend using these automations
enough. If you, again, are typing the
same thing over and over again, or
you're doing the same process over and
over again, automations are the way to
save you a ton of time. Now, let's talk
about loops. And in fact, I've been
thinking so much about loops, I actually
created a loop library, which I'm
announcing for the first time today. It
is a completely free library of loops
that I have used, that I've found others
have used, and if you have your own
loops and want to submit them, you can
do that. So, here it is,
signals.fordfuture.ai/loop-library.
I know it's long, I'll drop it down in
the description below. All you got to do
is bookmark it. Here's the loop library,
and we have a few right now, but I'm
going to be growing this list, and you
can always come here. It will always be
free, and I'm hosting it on here.now.
So, thank you to them for hosting and
partnering with me on the loop library.
All right, so, what is a loop? Well,
it's kind of exactly what it sounds
like. You have some kind of process that
loops over itself, right? Over and over
again. Very simple. But, what does that
actually mean? A loop contains three
things. One, some trigger to start the
loop. Two, some action that it does over
and over again. And then three, some
goal. Some end goal so that it just
doesn't run forever. And the loop will
stop once that goal is met. Now, back to
the loop library, what does that
actually mean in practice? A lot of
people talk about this in very hand-wavy
theoretical ways, wanted to actually
give you very concrete, practical loops
that you can start using today. And I'm
also going to explain why automations
and loops kind of go hand-in-hand a lot
of times. They don't always need to, but
it's nice to be able to kick off a loop
automatically. So, here's an example.
This is the overnight docs sweep loop.
Basically, what it does is it says,
"Each night, review the codebase in full
and make sure all documentation reflects
the latest changes from the previous
day. Update the documentation as needed,
then open a pull request with those
changes." The point is to keep all of
the documentation in my app, whether
it's the public-facing readme or
internal documentation, as up-to-date as
possible at all times. And so, I run
this in an automation and I say, "Okay,
at 1:00 a.m. run this automation." So,
it looks at all the changes that I made
from the previous day, compares it to
the documentation, and sees if there are
any gaps in the documentation, and
updates them appropriately. Here's
another amazing one that is really just
saved me a ton of time. This is called
the sub-50 ms page load loop. I
basically set up a loop for my agent to
go through my entire app, load every
single page, every single modal, every
single sidebar, everything. And if any
one of them loads in over 50 ms, I want
it to optimize the queries, optimize the
website, do whatever it needs to do to
make sure every single thing loads in
under 50 ms. So, the loop is continue
until everything loads in under 50 ms.
And I've had this thing run for hours
and hours and hours, and it really does
help. When it was finally finished, the
app was lightning fast. Now, I want to
show one more loop, and again, I'll drop
a link to the loop library down below so
you can check out all of them, and
please submit your loops. If you have
awesome loops that you use all the time
that are generalized and anybody can use
them, please go submit them. So, this is
called the production error sweep. I do
this every single night. I have an agent
kick off that looks at our production
logs and looks for any errors and
analyzes the error, tries to figure out
what caused it, writes up a fix for it,
and then submits a PR. And so, anytime
there's an error, and I really do have
full log coverage, which I would highly
recommend. I'll get to more of those
tips later. But, any error that happens,
any error that shows up in the log, when
I wake up, there's already a fix for it.
It's so cool. All right, so now that you
know about automations and loops, let me
give you some quick best practices.
Essentially, there is no reason to have
sub-optimal code at this point because
you can have 100% test coverage at all
times. You can kick off an automation
that checks if you do not have full
coverage and if you don't, write tests
to make sure you have full coverage.
There is really no reason not to. There
is no reason to have stale or missing
documentation for the same exact reason.
You kick off an agent and make sure all
of the functionality in your app, every
single day as it changes, gets updated
in that documentation. I cannot
recommend that enough. And then last,
have exhaustive logging. Log everything.
It really doesn't cost that much. You
can always have some like 30-day window
for logging or 7-day window for logging,
but you want to store all logs because
you could just task your agent with
fixing any errors that come up. It's so
brilliant, this flywheel of perfect
test, perfect documentation, and perfect
logging. Have these three in your code
base. I cannot recommend this enough.
All right, next let's talk about cloud
versus local agents. Most AI coding
tools have both. The big ones that
you've heard of definitely have both.
Cursor was really the first one to have
cloud agents, but Claude Code has it,
Codex has it, and what it basically
means is that you can spin up a
completely isolated environment for your
code base for each individual agent and
it's not running on your computer. And
this is really good for a lot of
reasons. Number one, it is infinitely
parallel because you're not depending on
the CPU or the RAM of your computer,
your home desktop or laptop to run a ton
of agents in parallel. You're using the
cloud. You are using a massive data
center to power this, so you really
don't have to think all that much about,
"Hmm, can I spin up 10, 20, 30 agents?"
It'll just work. Next, it is accessible
from anywhere. Most of these AI tools
have mobile apps, and you can log in and
manage your cloud agent from anywhere,
and it's very useful for coding on the
go. Now, of course, Claude Code and
Codex both allow you to control your
local agents remotely, but again, you
start running into some of those
bandwidth constraints because you're
running it locally. Next, one of the
most important reasons to use cloud
agents is that they run on completely
isolated environments, which means if
you have multiple agents all writing to
the same repo, they're not going to
conflict with each other, which is an
issue that I have all the time. Even if
I am spinning up new work trees locally
for every one of my agents, I still run
into these weird edge cases, and it
doesn't always work flawlessly like it
does if you're using a cloud agent.
Also, when you use cloud agents, there
are some really unique features,
dependent on which AI tool you're using.
For example, Cursor has this incredible
feature that gives you a video and
screenshots of the changes it made. You
don't have to ask for it, it just does
it. So, rather than just trusting that
it got something done, you can actually
see it. Check this out. So, here it is.
I added a new loading icon to my app,
and we can see there it is. And it
literally just showed me a video of it.
So, really cool, useful feature. Now,
there are some drawbacks to using cloud
agents. Let me tell you why sometimes
local is better. Number one is it's
faster.
It is much faster because you always
have an environment ready to go on your
local machine, versus the cloud, which
has to spin up a new environment for
every single agent that you kick off.
And there's a little bit of latency that
you pay there. It's not huge, but it is
something. Number two, you get more
control. When it's running on your own
computer, when you can actually see the
files being changed on your own
computer, you do have a better sense of
control over what's going on. Also,
cloud agents don't always have the
latest and greatest features released by
these AI coding tools. So, most likely,
the latest and greatest features are
going to ship with your local agents and
then later show up in the cloud. But, to
be honest, I am most likely going to be
moving my entire workflow to cloud
agents. There are just too many benefits
to moving all of this to the cloud,
especially when you start running a
bunch of agents in parallel, which, you
know, when I'm running 12, 15, 20 agents
in parallel on my computer, my computer
slows to a crawl. There's no avoiding
it. Now, I mentioned work trees, I just
want to touch on that one more time. All
right, so what is a work tree? A work
tree is a second working folder,
basically a copy of your repo, that is
separate from your other one. So, I
typically spin up work trees for every
agent. And so, that means each agent can
make changes to the same set of files,
to the same methods, and then the merge,
when I finally merge it later, that's
when we're going to resolve all the
conflicts. The problem with not using
work trees is if you have a bunch of
agents and they start writing to the
same file, they're going to get confused
and they're going to spin out of
control. It's very frustrating. So, try
to use work trees as much as possible.
Now, there is some latency that you pay
with using work trees, but overall,
there really isn't much downside to just
using work trees for all of your agent
threads. Now, work trees are very easy
to spin up. Here it is in Cursor. So,
here's my repo, here's the branch that
I'm using, and right here where it says
cloud, this is if you wanted to spin up
a cloud agent, you can select just the
repo itself and all of the agents are
going to work in the same work tree. And
if you click right here a new work tree,
that allows you to spin up a new work
tree for that agent. And so, that's it.
You're done. It's that easy. In Codex,
very similar. Right here where it says
cloud, you click it. Instead, you click
new work tree. Okay? And it
automatically selected main, but that's
it. Then when I kick it off, as you can
see with this thread, this one's using a
work tree. Now, the times that you
really don't need work trees is if you
have agents running on completely
different areas of the code base. One
last note about cloud agents. Make sure
to set them up with a full environment.
The same thing you would give your local
environment. So, local keys.env.local,
all of the things that you would give to
your local environment to make sure that
it runs well, to make sure it has access
to the different tools it needs, you
also need to do that in the cloud
environment. Each one, Cursor, Codex,
Cloud Code, Factory, they all have
interfaces on the web in which you can
go in and input your client secrets,
input your environment variables, and
you want to treat that as its own
environment and give it full power by
doing so. All right. Now, one of the
benefits of using a Cursor or a Factory
or a Devin is that you have multimodal
functionality. That means you're not
completely dependent on an Open AI
model. If you're using Codex, you're not
completely dependent on using an
Anthropic model. If you're using Cloud
Code, that's one of the benefits of
using one of these alternatives. But why
is multimodal important? If Anthropic or
Open AI has the most frontier model, the
best model on the planet, why don't I
just use that? Well, there's two
reasons. Speed and cost. Not everybody
has infinite tokens. And if you have to
be mindful about your token spending,
using multiple models is actually a
really good way to reduce your AI costs.
Plus, if you're not using the top model
all the time, you're actually going to
be able to complete tasks faster. And
let me show you how I do this. So,
here's an example of a multi-model
workflow, and you can set this up as a
skill, which is really cool. You can
define in a skill which model to use at
which point and for what use. So, for
example, let's say I'm building a brand
new feature. I will do the planning with
Fable. I want it to look at my entire
codebase. I want it to come up with a
detailed plan about how to actually do
and build this feature. But, once I come
up with this overall plan, I don't
necessarily need a Fable-level model to
execute it, to actually write the code.
In fact, a model like Composer is
actually excellent at writing code.
Maybe it's not as good at seeing around
corners and knowing every little bit
about the codebase and planning this
massive feature, but once that's done
and knows what to write, it is excellent
at doing so. And then last, maybe I do
the review with GPT 5.5. So, after
Composer wrote everything, rather than
sending it back to Fable, I'm going to
give it to a different model just to get
an alternative viewpoint on what was
written. So, review the code. And all of
this, again, can be written into a skill
very easily. All right, next. I have to
share this because it is an unsolved
problem. I have spoken to the OpenAI
team. I've spoken to the Cursor team.
I've talked to the best agentic
engineers on the planet, and this is an
unsolved problem. And that is merging
and deploys. And specifically, if you
have, like me, potentially a dozen
agents running in parallel, and you're
trying to get all of that code onto
production around the same time, it gets
so frustrating and so slow. So, let's
say you have one agent that is looking
to merge into main, they do so, and then
all of a sudden it kicks off the CI, it
kicks off the deploy process. Great, you
have to wait a couple minutes for that.
Then the second agent, right around the
same time, comes in and it's like,
"Okay, I want to get my code into main
as well. Let me do that." And then it
says, "Oh, wait, there's new changes
there. I haven't seen those changes.
Okay, let me rebase on my local repo,
let me rerun all of those tests, and
then let me try merging again. And then
once it finally does merge, it has to
actually run all of those CI and deploy
process again and again. And basically,
if you can imagine, you have a third one
and a fourth one, and they're all trying
to do the same thing on the same code
base, and they start stumbling over each
other. They start locking the commit
process, they start locking the deploy
process. What, they're all just waiting,
and then every single time one of them
gets through, every other one of them
has to restart the process completely.
It's broken. There really isn't a good
way to fix this. I've heard of a couple
ways, but none of them are perfect. The
only real thing to do is to just be
patient, and one trick that I sometimes
use is set up a bunch of PRs, and then
do batch commits. Just allow a single
agent to look at all the changes,
combine them, and then merge and deploy
all at once.
Definitely far from perfect. And in
fact, it's such a known problem that
literally today, Cursor just announced
they're building their own Git
alternative, specifically built for
agent scale deployment. So, this is
still a big problem. It's not really
solved, and hopefully it will be soon.
And again, one of the most important
things in this entire video that I want
you to go away with is automations and
loops. And if you want to learn more
about loops, I made a whole video about
it. Check it out right here.